Gene Basset Papers
Gene Basset Papers
- Cartoons, 1,319 items
  - Undated A-Q (Oversize 13)
    Just keeping up with the times: Republican Party, Ronald Reagan, Barry Goldwater
    Just remember...I'm an independent, deliberative body: Congress, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Know of any head that will stick?: Organization of American States, Lyndon B. Johnson, Dominican Republic
    LBJ is a hawk: Lyndon B. Johnson, crime
    Let an expert show you how: Charles De Gaulle, Vietnam War, France
    Let's not squabble. There's enough for both of us: famine, war, Pakistan, India
    Look it's settled...we'll have a nice simple wedding like the President's: Lyndon B. Johnson, Luci Johnson (wedding of)
    Look, Ma...no steering wheel: Republican Party
    Looks like another job for Superman: Lyndon B. Johnson, steel industry, strikes
    May I give you a lift?: Republican Party, John Lindsay
    Maybe we should at least think about drinking: Abdel Gamal Nasser, Hussein (of Jordan), Algeria, Syria, Israel
    Maybe you can use this: Vietnam War, elections, Republican Party
    Me, King Cong: Vietnam War, communism
    Metamorphosis: Wayne Morse, Middle East
    Mr. President...we must move with the utmost urgency!: Soviet Union, Israel
    Monument: Germany, Konrad Adenauer
    Motor's fine, but I'd add safety belts: stock market, Securities Exchange Commission
    Move over!: Nelson Rockefeller, Lyndon B. Johnson, elections
    Neutral: New York City, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Nobody in here but us suckers: Clay Liston
    No, no, no, Cassius...I am the greatest!: Muhammad Ali, Charles De Gaulle
    No one is gonna accuse us of peace!: Mao Zedong, Vietnam War, Ho Chi Minh
    Not so fast!: auto industry, safety
    Note, Senator, the lift and maneuverability of those frames: Congress
    Nourishment: nuclear weapons, Mao Zedong
    Now who's the greatest, Cassius?: Muhammad Ali, draft
    Old Viet Namese trick: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Open housing: race relations, Vietnam War
    Peking artillery: Mao Zedong
    Phew, now I can cough easier: smoking, Congress
    Poor visibility: Charles De Gaulle, nuclear weapons, France
    The Prophets: stock market, Lyndon B. Johnson, economy
    Quick, somebody...the hose: riots
  - Undated R-Y, untitled (Oversize 14)
    Resume stiff upper lip: Vietnam War, Ho Chi Minh, Mao Zedong
    Right turn ahead: Nelson Rockefeller, elections
    The rope is to keep her from falling: Greece, democracy
    Same game, new ball: politics, poverty
    Search me...I got enough just keeping up with our own corps: Maxwell Taylor, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr.
    Sherman was right: War on Poverty
    Sidewalks of New York: Robert F. Wagner, New York City, Republican Party, John Lindsay
    Some splinter: Republican Party
    Sorry about that, Adam baby: Adam Clayton Powell
    Sorry, but you're strictly fourth class: United States Postal Service
    ...Spearfishing, what else?: Robert F. Kennedy, Lyndon B. Johnson
    Spring planting: U. Thant, peace
    Still unscored upon: civil rights murder trial
    Sunken treasure?: Bobby Baker
    Support: Vietnam War, China
    Take your choice: Vietnam War, Republican Party
    Target: immigration
    Teddy says he's not supplying the prop: Hubert Humphrey
    Tell me...tell me all about our Utopia!: Alexey Kosygin, China, Karl Marx
    Testing...one, two, three, four...: voting rights, Congress
    There must be a launching spot somewhere: Britain, peace, Vietnam War, Harold Wilson
    There's dangerous talk of not releasing us: nuclear weapons, Soviet Union
    There's not much question, I'll run, puff, puff: George Romney
    This one's for Berkeley and this is for Oakland and this is for New York and this is for the Pentagon: protestors
    Time marches back: Vietnam War, Madame Ngo Dinh Nhu, Ngo Dinh Diem
    Tong war: Mao Zedong
    Touchdown: space exploration
    Tweet, tweet...BOOM, BOOM: Mike Mansfield, Everett Dirksen, voting rights, Lyndon B. Johnson
    20 years old and still standing: United Nations
    Us Americans don't need any firearms control: gun control
    The vanishing American: metal currency
    Waiting: Vietnam War
    War on-poverty: Sargent Shriver, Congress
    "We find results are better with this one: drug industry, consumers
    We, Peking brand smokers, would rather fight than switch!: Ho Chi Minh
    ...We'll have a barrel of fun: Congress
    We'll re-enter for a one million dollar, three-year contract: Don Drysdale, Sandy Koufax
    We're here to give you some lessons: Republican Party, Democratic Party, schools
    What do you say we pass a bill to go home?: laws
    What's my line?: John Charles Daly, Charles De Gaulle, Vietnam War, riots, Fidel Castro, Middle East
    Whoops: Chou En-lai, Afro-Asian conference
    Would you believe: an incompetent bookkeeper?: Christopher Dodd
    Yak-Yak attack: Vietnam War, Lyndon B. Johnson
    You understand it's nothing personal, Mr. Vice-president: Hubert Humphrey, Europe
    You'll have to wait until November 18 for my decision: George Romney, elections
    [American Medical Association dressed as a magician]: Medicare
    [U.S. Pavilion at Expo '67 with man running away]
    [Student Nonviolence Coordinating Committee person with large bat or club above head]
    [Man in tattered clothing holds a "Great Society" cup]
- Proofs, 7"x 10" 6 items
  - Circa 1960s (Oversize 12)
    Hi Sweetheart…Don't mind her…She's strictly my last resort: George Wallace, American Independent Party, Democratic Party
    How do we know it hasn't already leaked to the cowboys?: Richard Nixon, India, Pakistan
    It's either Henry Kissinger disguised as Howard Hughes or Hughes dressed like Kissinger
    The suspense is mounting in this Super Bowl, folks...when will coach Shula send in the President's play?: Vietnam War
    [possible Tet offensive, increased troop withdrawal]: Richard Nixon, Henry Kissinger, Vietnam War
    What part of Northern Ireland are you liberating tonight…a school, department store or the local pub?: Irish Republican Army